Does that sort of crime,
in this case murder,
have a name?
It's called a sadistic murder.
How do your studies
describe such a killer?
It's usually someone
who suffered emotional trauma
followed by long emotional isolation.
- Is there a purpose to the crime?
- Revenge.
Am I you, or are you me?
- Hurry up.
- Okay, okay.
Do you have my notebook?
- Emily, let's go. You don't need it.
- Okay.
Julia, can't we do this another night?
Emily, we should've been at the library
ten minutes ago.
- Let's go.
- Julia.
Come on. You like playing with fire.
- Good night, Aunt Esther.
- Good night.
Don't you girls believe
in having a little fun now and then?
- This is fun.
- Studying day and night?
Actually,
we're working on a project right now.
Abnormal psychology.
- Well, have a nice time.
- How's the book?
Incredibly great.
This poor girl
has just been swept off her feet
and ravished by the highwayman
who killed her father in a duel.
Very romantic.
- Aunt Esther, l--
- We have to go.
Bye.
Goodbye.
Back to Grimley,
back to the 35-yard line.
He passes the ball down the left.
It's complete to Elwes,
ladies and gentlemen.
- Good night, Uncle Harold.
- Good night.
Good evening, Miss Reese.
Thank you, Mrs. Reese.
Out of bounds at the 50-yard line.
It's the first--
Harold? Is that you?
Harold?
- Julia.
- Sorry.
Yes?
Very well, Emily.
- That work is in French, you know.
- Yes, ma'am.
Lined up for the kick-off.
Johnson is getting ready to kick.
Referee gives the whistle.
There's the kick.
It's deep into the end zone.
And Wilson has got the ball.
He's bringing it out,
ladies and gentlemen.
Hey. Hey!
Heading for the 25- 35-
45-yard line.
Esther? Esther, are you all ri--?
Now, you say you came home
at what time, Mr. Henderson?
About a half an hour ago.
I got here just before the cop--
I mean, you boys, got here.
And I can prove it. I got witnesses.
Why don't you get yourself
a cup of coffee,
and we'll talk some more?
Lieutenant,
found these boots around back.
They fit the prints in the flowerbed.
Thanks.
Mr. Scully.
Have you ever
seen these boots before, sir?
Yes, they're mine.
I keep them out in the shed
for gardening.
- But what has that got to do with--?
- They're yours, you're sure?
Well, of course I'm sure. But why?
Mr. Scully, can you explain
why the glass is broken
from the inside?
The inside?
And the intruder,
why would he
be wearing your boots, sir?
Uncle Harold?
What happened?
Esther is dead.
She's been murdered.
- Well, good morning.
- It's morning, all right.
As to the good part,
I'll tell you after I wake up.
Bad night?
Irving Turley's dog barked all night.
Then my hot-water heater went out
and I had to take a cold shower.
Then the car wouldn't start.
Well, why don't you talk to Turley
about that dog?
I would have, but I had to wake him up
to push the car.
What's the emergency?
Well, I couldn't find Charlene,
so I came down.
- You couldn't find Charlene?
- No.
Where was she?
I don't know.
That's why I couldn't find her.
- Well, who's the client?
- Harold Scully.
Harold Scully?
I'm going back to bed.
Ben, it's a homicide.
A homicide?
Harold Scully couldn't kill anybody.
He might bore a few people to death.
It's his wife. It happened last night.
Harold Scully?
I don't know, Frank.
I think you've got enough
to question him,
but I think
you're getting ahead of yourself.
- Well, how is that, Ben?
- What's your evidence?
Got it right here.
The boys found it this morning,
hidden in the basement.
How's it test?
It's all there. Hair, blood.
Now, the killer tried to clean it off,
but he botched it.
Wanna see your client now?
I'll have to discuss it
with my advisor.
Excuse me.
- They're gonna charge him.
- He's in the interview room.
I can't stand Harold Scully.
I used to like to play golf at Lakeside.
Somehow Harold always wound up
in the foursome.
He'd tell me how to stand,
how to look at the ball,
how to swing at it.
Half the time it'd go in the woods.
He'd run and find it
and point to it like a Labrador retriever.
Tell him I'm busy.
- You tell him you're busy.
- Tell him I moved to Philadelphia.
You tell him
you moved to Philadelphia.
You're a hard case, Tyler.
Harold,
I'm terribly sorry about Esther.
- Terribly sorry.
- Ben.
Thank you for coming, Ben.
Why would anyone
wanna kill her, Ben?
Why? Why?
Harold, you're gonna
have to turn me loose.
Sit down, Harold.
Ben, they think I did it.
Can you believe that?
Harold, let go of my hand.
Now, it's true
they are gonna arrest you.
I loved her, Ben.
I loved her. Why would I kill her?
Harold, you're gonna have to sit
by yourself.
Now, there's something
I wanna say to you.
Let me just say something
to you first.
I've always looked up to you.
I know I'm just some guy
who married a rich woman.
And I know
you've always thought I was a bore.
I am. I bore myself.
And I know you've avoided me.
I don't blame you.
I know I've made a pest out of myself
trying to get you to like me.
I miss our golf.
I don't know why I'm going on
about this.
I guess I should just say,
thank you for taking my case, Ben.
Thank you.
- Harold?
- Yes, Ben?
- I'll go see about bail.
- Thank you, Ben.
- There he is.
- Where is he?
- Over there.
- Yes.
Well, we got a locked house
and a locked shed.
If Harold didn't do it,
then somebody with keys
to both places did.
- The gardener lives above the garage.
- Is he there?
If he is, he's not answering.
Well, Harold says
that he's got keys to both places.
The gardener says that he was
at a place called Archie's Tavern
during the murder.
- Wanna see if he was?
- Okay.
How are you gonna plead him?
I don't know. Poor Harold.
I just don't think he did this.
He hadn't exercised since 1 948.
I don't think he's strong enough
to kill Esther.
Look, he had motive
and he had access.
He is the sole beneficiary
to Esther's will.
I don't believe
that masked-intruder story
for a heartbeat, do you?
- I don't know.
- And his boots.
His boots are the ones
that made the footprints.
You keep trying
to make me feel better, don't you?
There she is.
- Good morning.
- Morning.
People have been looking for you
all morning.
Were people concerned
or just curious, Dad?
Goodbye.
- We do have a case, you know.
- Yeah.
I've done a complete interview
with Harold Scully.
I booked him into a hotel
away from the press.
Oh, there's a couple who live in,
but they're away on vacation.
Anything else?
What about the sisters watching us
from the window up there?
Let's see.
''Parents killed when they were young.
Boarding schools all their lives.
Living here while at college.
Big inheritance from their father.
Brilliant students.''
- Where were they during the murder?
- They were at the library, studying.
- Do you want me to check it out?
- Yeah.
Will you be somewhere
where I can..?
I'll be around.
- Mrs. Reese?
- Yes?
I'm Charlene Matlock.
I'm an attorney
representing Harold Scully,
and I wanted
to ask you a couple of questions
about Emily and Julia McCullough.
What about them?
Well, now, were they both here
the night of the murder?
They came in at 8 and left at 1 0,
when the library closed.
And they were both here
the whole time?
- What are you suggesting?
- I'm not suggesting anything.
Well, let me put your mind at rest.
Shortly after 9:00
that particular evening,
Emily asked me
for a reference book.
And a few minutes before that,
I saw Julia up there, in the stacks.
- You're very precise.
- I suppose that is unusual.
Yeah. Well, thanks, Mrs. Reese.
Hey, you're Jim Henderson,
ain't you?
I heard about the murder
over at your place.
- Yeah.
- Hey, bartender.
Give me a beer over here
and another one for my friend.
- Heard you spent a lot of time in Nam.
- I don't talk about it.
I don't blame you,
since you spent your entire hitch
in the stockade at Fort Benning.
- How do you know that?
- Oh, I know a lot of things, Jimbo.
Like I know
the cops was looking you over
for the murder of Esther Scully.
You're a cop.
Cops do not wear $500 suits,
my friend.
I talk to cops. Cops talk to me.
And do you know
what the cops told me?
That you are the only other person
with a key to the shed
where Harold Scully keeps his boots.
I was here.
- Can you prove it?
- Ask anybody.
- And where were your keys?
- With me.
They're always with me.
You know,
Harold Scully is a dear friend of mine.
Scully is a killer,
and I hope he fries.
Harold was gonna fire you,
wasn't he, Jimbo?
He said that you
were a hopeless drunk
and he was gonna make sure
that you never got another job.
You're asking for it.
Don't move, Jimbo.
Don't move. See, I was in Nam.
I'm the real thing.
Green Beret, black belt, Silver Star.
I was a POW and an MIA.
It was so bad where we were,
we slept in body bags just in case.
Don't you move, Jimbo.
I'll take you out.
By the way, here are your keys.
Listen.
- Is somebody in the house?
- I think so.
Let's find out.
Aunt Esther's ghost?
What are you doing here?
Oh, I'm so sorry. Would you--?
Oh, would you look at that?
I'm sorry.
- I thought I was by myself.
- Who are you?
I'm Ben Matlock, Harold's lawyer.
- You must be his nieces.
- Yes, we are.
What gives you the right
to come in here?
Oh, I'm so sorry to intrude.
I have your Uncle Harold
in a hotel room.
He gave me the key,
and I thought
you girls were at the library.
Julia?
Harold said you were the one
that did the talking,
that Emily was real shy.
- Don't burn yourself with that.
- Oh, I'm not gonna burn anything.
Or anyone.
- What are you looking for?
- Silver polish.
Why?
Whoever killed your Aunt Esther
tried to clean that candlestick
before the police found it.
I can't find the silver polish.
If Harold tried to clean it,
where'd he put the polish?
- How are you gonna defend Harold?
- I don't know.
- Do you suspect Henderson?
- Well, I wouldn't rule him out.
Look.
- Silver polish.
- Isn't that interesting?
Because I just found this one.
I guess you can't
have too much silver polish.
Well, I'll be on my way.
And again, I'm...
Good night.
- Good night.
Julia?
Julia.
Julia!
- I missed you by two inches.
- Is that--? Is that what it was like?
Except for the two inches.
I forgot to tell you.
If you need anything, just call.
Good night.
Don't worry.
He's smart,
but he's not smart enough.
Good morning, Ben.
Are you ready to go to work?
- Well, just about.
- Good.
- Ms. Matlock.
- Mr. Burgess.
I called you last night,
but you weren't home.
I know.
- Good morning, Harold.
- Morning.
Ben, I'm very nervous.
Harold, the most important thing
you can do is sit up straight,
look right at the jury
like you haven't done anything
and you're not afraid of anything.
- How long do I have to do that?
- Till I tell you to stop.
Hi.
Lieutenant Daniels,
I show you People's Exhibit 5
and ask you if you recognise it.
Yes, it has my mark on it there.
Lieutenant, blood and particle tests
have been done on this candlestick.
It's stipulated by the defence that this
is the weapon that killed Mrs. Scully.
Please tell the court
where the candlestick was found.
Yes, it was found
wrapped in that newspaper
in the cellar
of the defendant's home.
So it was hidden in the cellar
of Harold Scully's house?
That is correct.
Lieutenant, you've already testified
that the glass door
was broken from the inside.
That the footprints in the flower bed
were made by the defendant's boots.
Now you tell us
that the murder weapon
was found in his home.
Lieutenant, as an experienced
investigator, what do you conclude
about the defendant's
claim that he saw an intruder?
Objection, Your Honour.
Improper opinion. Relevance.
I withdraw the question.
There's nothing further.
Any cross?
- No, Your Honour.
- You may step down.
Your Honour, the State rests.
Mr. Matlock?
Defence calls
James Henderson to the stand.
Mr. Henderson,
the night of the murder,
you were in town at Archie's Tavern.
Is that correct?
Yeah. I got witnesses.
And before you left home,
you locked up everything?
Sure, like always.
There are two sets of keys,
yours and Mrs. Scully's?
- That's right.
- Okay.
Now, the night of the murder,
how did you get home?
I got a ride from one of my buddies.
Would Mr. Robert Delaney
please stand, please?
That's the gentleman
who drove you home?
- Yeah.
- Now, Mr. Henderson,
I want you to think very carefully.
When you got home
the night of the murder,
you did not open the gate, did you?
Now, I can put Mr. Delaney
on the stand, he saw you.
- You climbed over it, didn't you?
- Yeah.
Why'd you do that?
I didn't have the damn keys.
Nobody else had them, either.
I found them in my apartment.
Mr. Henderson, you just testified
that you locked everything up.
If your apartment was locked,
how'd you get in?
Door was open.
So you, or someone else,
could've gone in your apartment,
gotten the keys,
and unlocked that shed.
It wasn't me.
But somebody could've unlocked
that shed and gotten those boots.
- Is that correct?
- That's right.
Okay. Yeah.
Now,
Mr. Henderson,
you don't drive, do you?
No.
I lost my licence.
Well, how did you get into town
the night of the murder?
- I got a ride.
- From whom?
Julia and Emily.
That's very nice of them.
Thank you. No further questions.
Good evening.
Fine library.
Researching the case.
''lnterpretation of Perception. ''
It's good. Julia'd enjoy this.
It's all about how sometimes
we see things that aren't there
and other times
we don't see what is.
Quiet.
Sorry.
Where's Julia?
I'd like to have a word with her.
She's here somewhere.
Let's go ask Miss Reese.
She may have seen her.
Mrs. Reese, have you seen Julia?
Yes, of course.
She's in the upper stacks, up there.
There she is. Julia.
- Where's Julia?
- Right over here.
I could have sworn--
Amazing how our eyes
can fool us sometimes.
Mr. Hudson
was interviewing your sister.
He tricked me. I thought it was you.
So did Mrs. Reese.
I don't think she's so certain now
it was you she saw in the stacks
the night of the murder.
We have to study.
One other thing.
Subpoenas for both of you.
You can come to court together.
It'll be like always.
- Well, that's it.
- Guess so.
- Take you to dinner?
- No thanks, Dad.
You're not trying to ask me where
I'm spending my evening, are you?
I respect your privacy.
Drop you off somewhere?
Good night.
Tyler, do you still have the keys
to the Scully house?
Now, why do you wanna go there?
Harold asked me
to pick up a few things.
Some soap that doesn't dry his skin,
some cologne that doesn't burn him,
little bedroom slippers,
and pyjamas with the horsies on them.
I didn't tell Dad because, well,
you know how he feels about Harold.
And you want to go alone?
Yeah. I mean, nobody's there,
and the girls are still studying.
You got it.
Horsies.
Is anyone there?
Julia?
Emily?
Help.
Help me.
Who's there?
Anybody here?
Open the door.
- Charlene?
- Dad?
Dad, I'm down here.
- Charlene.
- Dad.
- You all right?
- Yes.
I could've broken my neck.
We didn't know you were here.
We were just playing a game.
I'm sure you were.
Harold told me you were here.
I got worried.
- They did it, Dad.
- I know.
Morning, Julia.
What are you doing here?
I think we should talk.
Let you in on a secret.
I put a little cream cheese in the eggs.
Makes them richer.
There's toast. I couldn't find jelly.
Third cabinet, second shelf.
I gotta level with you, Julia.
I didn't wanna represent Harold,
but I'm really glad I am.
I never had a case like this one.
- Why is that?
- No motive.
Harold hated Esther.
Harold didn't kill Esther.
And you think you know who did?
Let's just say maybe I do.
But I still can't figure out...
No motive.
Emily!
You'll destroy your life
if you go along with Julia.
I don't know what to do.
Come with me, please,
before it's too late.
Leave her alone!
Are you all right?
Get out of here.
Both of you.
Let's go, Harold.
It worked, Ben.
Julia's hold on her's too strong.
What are we gonna do, Ben?
Ben, what are we gonna do?
Harold, we're both gonna fall down.
- I'll get to the bottom of it.
- I hope.
Emily,
where were you Wednesday night,
the night of the murder?
- I was at the library.
- With your sister?
That's right.
But don't you usually have
bridge club on Wednesday night?
- Yes.
- I bet you're pretty good.
Yes, I am.
In fact, you haven't missed
a Wednesday of bridge
in over a year, have you?
No.
But the night of the murder, you
didn't go to your bridge party, did you?
No.
Objection. Relevancy.
Your Honour, we're looking toward
developing facts
to indicate another person, or persons',
commission of this terrible crime.
Very well, but try to move it along.
Now, Emily,
why didn't you play bridge
that Wednesday night?
I told you, I was in the library.
Must've been something
very important.
- An exam?
- No.
- A paper?
- Yes.
On what subject?
It was for my Econometric seminar.
If I had spoken to Mr. Harvey Gleason,
your professor,
at his office over at Campbell Hall,
I would bet that he wouldn't have been
able to recall any such assignment.
You're making me nervous.
Oh, take your time, take your time.
- It was for Russian Lit.
- No, it wasn't.
And it wasn't for Statistics,
or Economic History,
or Advanced Monetary Theory, either.
You didn't have any papers.
You didn't have any tests.
Isn't it true you didn't play bridge
because Julia made you
go to the library?
No.
And didn't you go there
to give your sister an alibi?
No.
Emily,
when you were very young,
your parents died in a fire,
didn't they?
Yes.
And you always felt bad about that,
didn't you?
Even guilty?
Yes.
Did you know that fire
was caused by a broken gas main?
No.
I have the fire-department
report right here.
Julia didn't tell you that, did she?
She needed for you
to feel responsible
for the fire
and the death of your parents
because you used to like
to play with matches.
Emily,
if you'll help me, if you'll be strong,
you can end the domination
of your sister over you right now.
Leave my sister alone.
Why are you letting him
attack her like this?
Can't you see what he's doing to her?
He's a liar. Liar!
Order. Order in the court.
One more word out of you, young lady,
and I'll have you in contempt.
No further questions.
I have no questions
of this witness, Your Honour.
You may step down.
Julia,
the court isn't finished with you.
Your Honour, I call Julia
McCullough to the stand.
Now, Julia, you're a very smart
young woman, aren't you?
No, not really.
I've got your records right here.
You graduated college at 1 9,
already have your Master's degree.
Working on your Ph.D.
in Clinical Psychology, aren't you?
Yes.
Your Master's thesis was on
resulting criminal behaviour
in the emotionally deprived
and intellectually gifted adolescent.
You can almost be an expert witness
in this case.
I don't think so.
Maybe you could help me out.
Based on your research,
what sort of person
commits a motiveless crime?
Actually, there have been some
case studies on that subject.
Well, does that sort of crime,
in this case, murder, have a name?
It's called a sadistic murder.
How do your studies
describe such a killer?
It's usually someone
who suffered emotional trauma
followed by long emotional isolation.
If we were to meet such a person,
how would they appear
on the surface?
Very self-reliant.
Do they usually show
lack of emotion, sometimes total?
Sometimes, yes.
- Is there a purpose to the crime?
- Revenge.
Against whom?
They're rebelling against the world.
They find it cruel and unfeeling.
Do they think they're invulnerable?
Some of them.
- Superior?
- Yes.
Do you consider Harold Scully
to be a superior person?
That's not for me to say.
If he were, probably no one would be
able to prove he committed this crime.
I wouldn't know.
If you committed this crime,
would anyone be able to prove it?
Objection. Calls for speculation.
Sustained.
Do you consider yourself superior?
No.
Now, Julia,
you stole Mr. Henderson's keys
the night you drove him into town,
didn't you?
- No.
- Then made your sister
impersonate you in the library.
- No.
- Then you killed your Aunt Esther
to prove you could commit
the perfect crime
and were therefore
better than everyone else.
- No.
- Then you and your sister
hid this candlestick
in the basement for the police to find.
- Of course not.
- Who did?
- Uncle Harold.
- I don't think so.
I just noticed something that somehow
evaded me until a moment ago.
If it had been a snake,
it would've bitten me.
When does the paper arrive
at the house?
- In the morning.
- What time?
About 6:00.
Well, Harold couldn't have used this
newspaper to wrap the candlestick.
Why not?
Read the day of the week.
Read it.
- It's Thursday's paper.
- I didn't hear you.
It's Thursday's paper.
And Uncle Harold
was taken into custody by the police
Wednesday night, wasn't he?
- Yes.
- So, what does that mean?
It means this candlestick
was placed in the basement
after Harold was taken
to police headquarters.
Who was at the house
Thursday morning, Julia?
The police were with you.
They know that you and Emily
were alone.
Only you and your sister
could've placed this candlestick
in the basement.
Your Honour, in fairness
and in the interest of justice,
State moves for dismissal.
Motion is granted.
This court is adjourned.
- Congratulations, Harold.
- I'm so relieved.
Isn't he great?
Oh, Ben. Ben, thank you, thank you.
My very own nieces.
- Thank you, Ben, thank you.
- Ben. Ben.
- Congratulations.
- Thank you.
Charlene, Dale and Stephanie
will meet us at the restaurant.
I'll see you there.
I'll see you tomorrow, Dad. Harold.
- Oh, Charlene, thank you.
- You're very welcome.
Oh, Ben, Ben, thank you, thank you.
And we'll meet
at the club tomorrow for golf.
- No golf.
- How about lunch?
Actually, I don't eat on Tuesdays.
Actually, Tyler and I
have a case in Philadelphia.
You've got a case in Philadelphia.
www.tvsubtitles.net